High above the trenches 14 days is a long life...This is the 15th day!
Aces High is a action, drama, war film directed by Jack Gold.
The first World War is in its third year and aerial combat above the Western Front
is consuming the nation's favored children at an appalling rate.
By early 1917, the average life-span of a British
pilot is less than a fortnight.
Such losses place a fearsome strain on Gresham,
commanding officer of the squadron.
Aces High recreates the early days of the Royal Flying Corps with some magnificently staged aerial
battles, and sensitive direction presents a moving portrayal of the futilities of war.
Maj. John Gresham, played by Malcolm McDowell.
Capt. 'Uncle' Sinclair, played by Christopher Plummer.
Lt. Crawford, played by Simon Ward.
Lt. Stephen Croft, played by Peter Firth.
Lt. 'Tommy' Thompson, played by David Wood.
Headmaster, played by John Gielgud.
Aces High is a 1976 war film directed by Jack Gold, starring Malcolm
McDowell, Peter Firth, Christopher Plummer and Simon Ward.
An Anglo-French production, the film is based on
the 1928 play Journey's End by R.
Sherriff, with additional material from fighter ace
Cecil Lewis's memoir, Sagittarius Rising.
The screenplay was written by Howard Barker.
Aces High turns the First World War trench warfare of Journey's End into the aerial
battles fought in 1917 by the Royal Flying Corps (RFC) above the Western Front.
The film covers a week of a squadron where the high death rate
puts an enormous strain on the surviving pilots.
Many characters and plot lines are loosely based on those of Journey's End: the idealistic new officer who is killed at the end, and whose sister is the girlfriend of his tough but alcoholic commanding officer, the kindly middle-aged
second-in-command (known as "Uncle" by the younger officers) who is killed on a dangerous intelligence-gathering mission ordered by the top brass, and the officer whose claims of neuralgia are taken to be cowardice.
The film explores themes of post-traumatic stress disorder (ptsd),
world war i, pilot, royal flying corps (rfc), dogfight.
The tone is emotional.